[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a928", "question": "Where is the Bowling Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Arlington, Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f4", "question": "What was the first TV soap opera to regularly broadcast hour-long shows?", "answer": "Another World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae0e", "question": "In which decade was Greenpeace founded?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f4", "question": "What day is the Super Bowl always played on?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339971", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", how many children do Apu and Manjula have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d8", "question": "What is the more common name for the fruit \"Citrus maxima\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bb49364247bf200fb8a2", "question": "What is Eddie's last name in the TV show \"The Courtship of Eddie's Father\"?", "answer": "Corbett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ae", "question": "What did Leonard Nimoy need a new pair of every few days in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef92a66ce05a3942286e86", "question": "What was the first animated TV series to win an Emmy?", "answer": "Huckleberry Hound Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339667", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Lisa's teacher?", "answer": "Miss Hoover", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec7234257c9fcac0ce7197b", "question": "As of 2020, who were the last two horses to win the Kentucky Derby and Triple Crown?", "answer": "American Pharoah and Justify", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ec2008d98002fdd633b7", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a2", "question": "What makes popping corn pop?", "answer": "The water stored inside the kernel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a7ef6c0f9723ab15cb60", "question": "What is the longest someone has gone without sleeping?", "answer": "266 hours", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b974", "question": "Which ice skater was attacked by one of her arch rivals?", "answer": "Nancy Kerrigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e4", "question": "What did Henry Shrapnel invent?", "answer": "Exploding shell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a433", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a882", "question": "The former penal colony of Devil's Island is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a7", "question": "What two countries edge the Victoria Falls?", "answer": "Zimbabwe and Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3f1e44f0f6af5b066650", "question": "Morello is a variety of which fruit?", "answer": "Cherry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe767f8eec85e375820b29c", "question": "Which city is considered the birthplace of democracy?", "answer": "Athens, Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd970e223c87fd04dd15e49", "question": "What U.S. state was the first to ratify the Constitution?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b9", "question": "Who wrote and also starred in the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea461dff048f679a45ab9e", "question": "What is the Hawaiian name for yellow fin tuna?", "answer": "Ahi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67b", "question": "What is the main source of food for the badger?", "answer": "Earthworms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b5c901dd7bf43be5e7d5", "question": "What sporting event is referred to as \"The Run for the Roses\"?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b254", "question": "In what city did Rosa Parks refuse to move to the back of the bus?", "answer": "Montgomery, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ccf7cb5b37b32637bdc44ca", "question": "How many neck bones do humans have?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b2f84fda37788a9a1dbf", "question": "Who is Tasmania named after?", "answer": "Abel Tasman", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b0d6e662d71a53650fcd", "question": "What is the name of Argus Filch's pet cat?", "answer": "Mrs. Norris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5de65a4cf89b9ec3da2d335e", "question": "Who played Bruce Wayne in the 1989 film \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b36df71c3f17ccc40c8e07", "question": "Who wrote and directed the 1999 film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "M. Night Shyamalan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8c", "question": "Who began his career as \"the Cherokee Kid\", the trick roper in Texas Jack's Wild West Circus?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f8", "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River empty?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be08", "question": "Which of Santa's reindeer have names that mean \"thunder\" and \"lightning\" in German?", "answer": "Donner and Blitzen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c4e7fbde8045e48466a4", "question": "Approximately how many snow crystals fall each winter?", "answer": "One septillion -- That's a trillion trillion, or a one with 24 zeroes behind it. Scientists insist no two flakes are the same.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6670ba5bfecdd737e086a", "question": "What US state was the first to ban drivers from talking on handheld devices?", "answer": "New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b42601dd7bf43be5e7bc", "question": "What company was formerly named Cadabra Inc.?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339961", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Milhouse's last name?", "answer": "Van Houten", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca1", "question": "What Crayola color became \"midnight blue\" in 1958?", "answer": "Prussian blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898e", "question": "What was the follow-up book to \"Bridget Jones's Diary\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596761c52b59efe0e9417ea5", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04c", "question": "Elvis's \"A Little Less Conversation\" was remixed into a 2002 hit single by which musician?", "answer": "Junkie XL", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca35", "question": "What instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points on opposite sides of an object?", "answer": "Caliper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85d", "question": "What is the World's 9th largest country by land area?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddbbe6ce05a3942286d93", "question": "According to the Jim Croce song, what is Leroy Brown meaner than?", "answer": "Junk yard dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c2749076251badbeace", "question": "How many U.S. Presidents fathered no children?", "answer": "Five -- George Washington, James Polk, Warren Harding, James Buchanan, and Andrew Jackson fathered no children.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e62", "question": "Until Ben-Hur broke its record, what was the bestselling novel of the nineteenth century?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64f", "question": "From which US university did Richard Nixon obtain a law degree?", "answer": "Duke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c304", "question": "What percentage of the cucumber is water?", "answer": "96", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbce", "question": "In the card game Bridge, what is considered the highest of the four suits?", "answer": "Spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39d", "question": "What did James Ritty invent in 1879?", "answer": "Cash register", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fe", "question": "Which country were the 2010 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c366", "question": "What shape is the piston in a \"Wankel\" engine?", "answer": "Triangular", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b358a0b5db0d66a186cb550", "question": "Which ocean does the African country, Burundi, has access to?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40c", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed2", "question": "What was the subtitle of the 1993 sequel to \"Hot Shots\"?", "answer": "Part Deux", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1aa", "question": "What Elvis Presley film is set in England?", "answer": "Double Trouble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd8937e83c707845b2176", "question": "In what State were the exteriors of the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\" filmed?", "answer": "The exteriors of the film took place outside a soon-to-be demolished reformatory in Mansfield, Ohio.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c74ec223966ae8f884a", "question": "In 1967, what band released the hit song \"Ruby Tuesday\"?", "answer": "The Rolling Stones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c36c2b316f4693fb67a8", "question": "At which famous venue is a giant Christmas tree displayed each year in New York City?", "answer": "Rockefeller Center", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a562", "question": "The Gila River flows into what river?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d2", "question": "In which comic book did Batman make his first appearance?", "answer": "Detective Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e147a6b6ca6dac04a20ca4e", "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?", "answer": "1803", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2f", "question": "Laetrile is most often associated with the pit of which fruit?", "answer": "Apricot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf8", "question": "In what year was the Twinkie invented?", "answer": "1930", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c65", "question": "What duo published the story of \"Hansel & Gretel\" in 1812?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339369", "question": "What was Jane Fonda's first movie?", "answer": "Tall Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c95", "question": "On what planet was Superman born?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f1746682715b82711ce0", "question": "Amor Vincit Omnia a Latin phrase meaning what?", "answer": "Love conquers all", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339779", "question": "Which original song from Titanic won an Oscar in 1997?", "answer": "My Heart Will Go On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c359", "question": "On which planet did the spacecraft Venus 8 land in 1972?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee4", "question": "What American League Baseball Coach coached the Philadelphia Athletics for 50 straight years?", "answer": "Connie Mack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d2", "question": "Which English spa city, the setting for many of her novels, boasts the Jane Austen Center?", "answer": "Bath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9b", "question": "What was the fictional town that was the setting for the soap opera \"All My Children\"?", "answer": "Pine Valley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bf", "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5e4d6ce05a3942286e31", "question": "Which hockey team did Wayne Gretzky play for in the 1980s?", "answer": "Edmonton Oilers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac7", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy in the movie \"E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Reese's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f72e9a9e54d890926f6ee", "question": "What is the only country that displays the Bible on its national flag?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd08", "question": "What of the so-called original six teams was the NHL's first US franchise?", "answer": "The Boston Bruins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b8", "question": "What musical instrument does Sherlock Holmes play for relaxation?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c6220775fa611bce67cf", "question": "What was the original name of Chicago's Willis Tower?", "answer": "Sears Tower -- Sears Tower, the former home to Sears Roebuck and Company, was the tallest building in the world from 1973 to 1998.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2100131a458464a93c43b", "question": "Sulaco is a port city in which Joseph Conrad novel?", "answer": "Nostromo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ad", "question": "What is usually added to tin to make solder?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e12a06d333868d34d724", "question": "Which Roman Emperor\u2019s \"Edict of Milan\" made Christianity legal?", "answer": "Constantine I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfd", "question": "What was the last name of Dennis the Menace's older neighbor that Dennis would consistently bother?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9053601dd7bf43be5e87a", "question": "What does \"In vino veritas\" translate into?", "answer": "In wine is truth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9d", "question": "How did Scarlett and Rhett\u2019s daughter die, in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Fell off a horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f4a8ff048f679a45aac8", "question": "Koumpounophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Buttons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f91", "question": "What is Goldfinger's first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5921fe82a4edfd43a087adcf", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c453", "question": "What part of the cinnamon tree becomes the spice?", "answer": "The bark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339949", "question": "What character ran the general store on both \"Green Acres\" and \"Petticoat Junction\"?", "answer": "Sam Drucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a5a820565ad31a57c7cf", "question": "Which Mediterranean island once campaigned to become a U.S. state?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e7", "question": "What US state has been led by Woodrow Wilson and Jim McGreevey?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dc", "question": "At the delta of the Danube River, what body of water does it flow into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339786", "question": "Who was the lead singer of \"The Crickets\"?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52bc11bf59ab7d2e38104", "question": "With what skill did Odysseus defeat Penelope\u2019s suitors?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb2", "question": "According to an old saying, \"An ounce of what is worth a pound of cure\"?", "answer": "Prevention", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f76", "question": "What was Tom Petty's backing band?", "answer": "The Heartbreakers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b56", "question": "On what date did Otis Redding die?", "answer": "December 10, 1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a853", "question": "What new Wonder of the World is located in Peru?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98c", "question": "What musical instrument is played to wake up soldiers?", "answer": "Bugle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c9250775fa611bce67e8", "question": "What is hummus made from?", "answer": "Chickpeas -- Hummus is Arabic for \"chickpeas.\" It is a Middle Eastern dish common throughout the Mediterranean region and beyond.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f33d01dd7bf43be5e816", "question": "In the US, what does AARP stand for?", "answer": "American Association of Retired Persons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4301ff048f679a45ab7f", "question": "What is a hominid?", "answer": "An Upright-Walking Primate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7e759b24f84e0b9f9ffb8", "question": "Which Star Wars villain shares a voice with the narrator of the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "Darth Vader", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a675", "question": "Richmond is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4d01dd7bf43be5e767", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "The keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7357feec85e375820b24c", "question": "Who said, \"Personally I\u2019m always ready to learn, although I do not always like being taught.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980b", "question": "Which ballad by the band Poison is about a Vietnam veteran and the homeless?", "answer": "Something To Believe In", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a856", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7e7fff048f679a45ac10", "question": "Belonephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pins and needles?", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c578fbde8045e48466ad", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590680ddff9c0647b50a808f", "question": "What company was founded in October, 2016, to relaunch an all-electric vehicle that had previously failed?", "answer": "Fisker Inc.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cf", "question": "What was Walt Disney's first feature-length animated film?", "answer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd1", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"H\"?", "answer": "Hotel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913e", "question": "Whose final opera was called \"Death in Venice\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Britten", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25d1bb63e5727cf5a4862", "question": "Michael Jackson's video for \"Black or White\" featured which famous child actor?", "answer": "Macaulay Culkin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76e2deec85e375820b2db", "question": "Where did bungee jumping originate?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7e77ff048f679a45ac0f", "question": "Batrachophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339430", "question": "What comedic duo of the 1920s and 1930s were real-life best friends?", "answer": "Laurel & Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0e", "question": "Comedian Jon Stewart was born in which US city?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339219", "question": "What actor is known as \"The Fonz\"?", "answer": "Henry Winkler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afad", "question": "Off of which European coastline was the \"Battle of Trafalgar\" fought?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e4", "question": "What is Chicago's main international airport?", "answer": "O'Hare", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddc6f6ce05a3942286d9c", "question": "Which actor starred in both of the only Christmas movies released in 1989?", "answer": "Johnny Galecki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b849", "question": "What is the highest hand in straight poker?", "answer": "A royal flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8c", "question": "Goitre is mostly caused by what deficiency?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a78", "question": "What William Faulkner novel presented its plot from four different points of view?", "answer": "The Sound and the Fury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b6", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Dominion\" state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa1", "question": "What legendary jazz trumpeter was nicknamed \"Satchmo\"?", "answer": "Louie Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded09aea2747c8aff16d2a", "question": "What is extracted from the ore cassiterite?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe775dbeec85e375820b312", "question": "Where are the Baalbek Roman ruins located?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c7420775fa611bce67d7", "question": "What is the whiskey that evaporates from its barrel called?", "answer": "\"Angels\u2019 share\" -- About 2% per year is lost. It gets its name because the missing liquid presumably evaporates to the heavens.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ba", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the west?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c118", "question": "Sapporo beer was first brewed in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0f", "question": "What character, created by Hugh Lofting, could talk to animals?", "answer": "Dr. Dolittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b649", "question": "What piece of the wardrobe was referred to as \"Teddy Boy\" in the 1950s?", "answer": "Drainpipe trousers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969d", "question": "Ben Kingsley won an Oscar in 1982 for which movie directed by Richard Attenborough?", "answer": "Gandhi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a9", "question": "Who had the job of eliminating maverick androids?", "answer": "Blade runners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b4", "question": "Who on TV played Jeeves to Hugh Laurie's Bertie Wooster?", "answer": "Stephen Fry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed289aec223966ae8f890c", "question": "What was the name of Patrick Swayze's character in \"Ghost\"?", "answer": "Sam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66c8ca5bfecdd737e0895", "question": "What was Instagram originally called?", "answer": "Burbn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbae7ab0738315b1fb74e26", "question": "What mathematician published \"Elements\" and influenced the study of modern geometry?", "answer": "Euclid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338951", "question": "What job does Joe teach to Pip in Great Expectations?", "answer": "Blacksmith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c971", "question": "What is botany the study of?", "answer": "Plants\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ce", "question": "In what 2006 film does a family travel in a VW microbus to get to a beauty pageant?", "answer": "Little Miss Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee9", "question": "In \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\", Eliza's famous flight across the ice floes takes place on what frozen river?", "answer": "The Ohio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be68", "question": "What is Yankee Stadium's nickname?", "answer": "The House That Ruth Built", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a5", "question": "What car lost 96 percent of its sales in the four years after the publication of Ralph Nader's \"Unsafe at Any Speed\"?", "answer": "Chevrolet Corvair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd703e347d002c297e4be", "question": "Which pioneer of modern nursing had a cat called Bismark?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65551ae7e414034b5aeaf", "question": "Greek Mythology, who was responsible for the abduction of Persephone which led to the four seasons of the Earth?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e0", "question": "How many referees are there in a soccer game?", "answer": "One", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339347", "question": "What does CSI stand for in the TV show by the same name?", "answer": "Crime Scene Investigation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3cff44f0f6af5b066636", "question": "\"Domingo\" is Spanish for what?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338915", "question": "Who killed the Minotaur?", "answer": "Theseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea824fff048f679a45ac20", "question": "What color is second from the top in a rainbow?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c433", "question": "What is the fruit of the rose?", "answer": "Rose hip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae08", "question": "Which New England state was an independent republic for 14 years before joining the union?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7bdef877e98cb9777895b", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K-2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8de", "question": "Which Scandinavian nation has a yellow cross on its flag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e6", "question": "What year was carbon 14 first discovered?", "answer": "1940", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2966c9bff04efae6d756", "question": "Who wrote the music for \"Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat\"?", "answer": "Andrew Lloyd Webber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81e", "question": "What song contains the line \"I feel stupid and contagious\"?", "answer": "Smells Like Teen Spirit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65e", "question": "How many of the engines can a 747 pilot see from his cockpit window?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2d", "question": "What dessert consists of beaten egg whites, sugar, and cream of tartar?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7352deec85e375820b246", "question": "Who was President Nixon's first vice president?", "answer": "Spiro T. Agnew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b745", "question": "What Biblical name literally means \"the sunny one\"?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a341", "question": "In movies, who was the first actor to portray Wolf Man?", "answer": "Lon Chaney Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b9e9364247bf200fb892", "question": "What is a group of fish referred to as?", "answer": "Shoal and school", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe36d7d0ada16518afdc042", "question": "What does \"UL\" in a circle mean, when found on electrical equipment?", "answer": "Underwriters Laboratory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c867", "question": "What is the heaviest chemical element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Uranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173fea44491cbd7c5a17b8", "question": "The Battle of Austerlitz took place during which war?", "answer": "Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f564a533a95c66dc4fe750", "question": "Which character did Jack Nicholson portray in the 1974 film \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J. Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab04", "question": "Mount Vernon is located in which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc37", "question": "What US city was basketball player Michael Jordan born in?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ec", "question": "What fish became popular at fish stores after the release of \"Finding Nemo\"?", "answer": "Clown fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9b06ebfabb9c85d8a981", "question": "\"Four legs good, two legs bad\" is a quotation from which novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a2", "question": "How many sides does a nonagon have?", "answer": "9", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339152", "question": "What year did Stephen King publish the horror novel \"Pet Sematary\"?", "answer": "1983", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cbcc877e98cb97778a1f", "question": "Thimphu is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bda", "question": "What was the name of the three-headed god that guarded the gates to Hades?", "answer": "Cerebus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a3", "question": "In what movie does Sean Penn play a mentally challenged man?", "answer": "I Am Sam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c1877e98cb977789d6", "question": "Where are the Whitsunday Islands located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173c1044491cbd7c5a17a2", "question": "How did Monday get its name?", "answer": "Moon's day -- It was formerly spelled moned\u00e6i, which comes from the Old English words m\u014dnand\u00e6g and m\u014dnd\u00e6g (\u201cmoon's day\u201d).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399de", "question": "Who was the only one of the six main characters on \"Friends\" to not get married at any time on the show?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601219cf63c99d48cd169afb", "question": "What is someone who shoes horses?", "answer": "A farrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2af", "question": "According to the title of the film, what is the profession of Ace Ventura?", "answer": "Pet Detective", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff513b4ff04d658268c92de", "question": "What naval battle between Mark Antony and Octavian is often said to mark the beginning of the Roman Empire?", "answer": "The\u00a0Battle of Actium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccc", "question": "The song \"Suite: Judy Blue Eyes\" was inspired by Stephen Stills' breakup with whom?", "answer": "Judy Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfff811cf6db9ac4808d0e", "question": "What are the three official languages of Luxembourg?", "answer": "French, German, and Luxembourgish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20ed931a458464a93c42b", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0dd", "question": "Checkpoint Charlie was the gate that divided the east and west portions of what city?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b0", "question": "What 2 planets in the solar system are typically synonymous with the man and woman?", "answer": "Mars and Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015dfa4fe83fe1f2a824b7c", "question": "What queen defeated and killed Cyrus the Great of Persia?", "answer": "Tomyris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b654", "question": "The hymn for what branch of the US military begins with the line: \"From the halls of Montezuma\"?", "answer": "Marine Corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339846", "question": "What TV family includes Gomez, Morticia, and Pugsley?", "answer": "Addams Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399af", "question": "In the movie \"Basic Instinct\", Michael Douglas plays a cop in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bedb", "question": "Which musical instrument was invented by Henry Schluter?", "answer": "Vibraphone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339503", "question": "Who provided the voice of Iago in Disney?s Aladdin?", "answer": "Gilbert Godfried", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be94", "question": "What Toyota sports car model had to be renamed the \"Celica Sports Package\" in January 2005?", "answer": "Tsunami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3c", "question": "What chain did Ray Kroc build?", "answer": "McDonald's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339529", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for her role as Lisa Rowe in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Angelina Jolie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45e", "question": "What is mixed with clay, baked in a kiln, and then pulverized in order to make Portland cement?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbe", "question": "What was meant to happen to anyone who drank from the river Lethe?", "answer": "Lost their memory", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c511", "question": "What are deheaded, deveined and sorted by size in a Laitram machine?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c5c50775fa611bce67cb", "question": "Turmeric is a popular spice that is used in Asian dishes.  What other use does it have?", "answer": "Turmeric is also a powerful anti-inflammatory often used in traditional medicine.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a399", "question": "What German city is famed for a scent it produces?", "answer": "Cologne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc6beec223966ae8f8887", "question": "What is Neo's official name in the film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Anthony A. Anderson, which is why Agent Smith refers to him as \"Mr. Anderson\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a7f720565ad31a57c7f1", "question": "What President\u2019s fondness for pork rinds made sales of the snack boom?", "answer": "George H. W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a6", "question": "What does Montana's motto \"oro y plata\" mean in English?", "answer": "Gold and silver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae95a3574a5ce6b56b8257", "question": "What are formed by Orogeny?", "answer": "Mountains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01f", "question": "Which of the two leads of 1995's movie \"Friday\" didn't appear in either of the sequels?", "answer": "Chris Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a273", "question": "Who was the male star of the 1997 film \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b221", "question": "What city was Rasputin killed in?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae69", "question": "What did Ronald Reagan disclose he was suffering from in 1994?", "answer": "Alzheimer's Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339350", "question": "Who were Alex Keaton's parents on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Elyse and Steven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e10", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab5", "question": "What is the technical term for earwax?", "answer": "Cerumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab17", "question": "Where's the famed Arch of Hadrian?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb04", "question": "What was the original designation of the Pioneer 10 space probe?", "answer": "Pioneer F", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b587", "question": "When was Gatorade first introduced?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339890", "question": "Which of the Marx brothers had a mustache and smoked cigars?", "answer": "Groucho Marx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339109", "question": "What popular book did Viktor Frankl write in 1946?", "answer": "Man's Search for Meaning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1a", "question": "The TV show \"Ugly Betty\" is based on what Venezuelan show?", "answer": "Yo soy Betty la fea", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b710", "question": "What soft drink company adopted Santa as a spokesman in the 1930's?", "answer": "Coca Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1689af7c52aae91cc07c9", "question": "In the game of darts, what is a score of 26 commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Breakfast, or bed 'n' breakfast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f2", "question": "In the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\", how many of the Ryan brothers were soldiers?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b698", "question": "What is vadouvan?", "answer": "Indian spice with a French twist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e5", "question": "What is the study of insects called?", "answer": "Entomology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab81", "question": "What country borders Guinea to the south?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c9", "question": "What part of New York was called \"broken land\" by the Dutch?", "answer": "Brooklyn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339625", "question": "Who starred as Danny Ocean in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a2", "question": "People suffering from hyalophagia do what?", "answer": "Eat glass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a92820565ad31a57c7fe", "question": "Who was the first director of the FBI?", "answer": "J. Edgar Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c952", "question": "The angel shark is commonly referred to by what other name?", "answer": "Monkfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a46", "question": "What album was the first to be certified platinum by the RIAA?", "answer": "\"Their Greatest Hits\" by Eagles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c34d7815febcc896f9256", "question": "What is the capital of Sao Tome and Principe?", "answer": "Sao Tome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015de83fe83fe1f2a824b6c", "question": "What actor was one of the most decorated American combat soldiers of World War II?", "answer": "Audie Murphy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c90", "question": "What 1969 Kurt Vonnegut novel is subtitled \"The Children's Crusade\"?", "answer": "Slaughterhouse-Five", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a37", "question": "Who recorded the multi-platinum 1970s album \"Bat Out of Hell\"?", "answer": "Meat Loaf", "category": "entertainment"}]